[opening theme music playing]
WORDS THAT SLIPPED OUT
- [all panting]
- [rhythmic drumbeats in distance]
I never get tired of hearing that sound.
Is there a festival going on?
It's registration time for the turf war.
We sign up for a turf war?
I guess there will be fighting.
[Bean] Nah, it's not done
that way these days.
The four gangs
that control the Black Market,
they set fire to their blood
and compete on the strength of the scent.
Wow. The essence of being a beast.
[chuckles] And here's some news for ya.
It sounds like Melon is in the turf war.
[tribal drumbeats]
[announcer on mic] This is the final call
for any last entries.
Two minutes until registration closes.
[all exclaiming softly]
[Legoshi] I don't see Melon.
[Bean] Huh? He's not here.
I guess we're too late.
Sorry, let's head back.
Wait a sec. Just hold on.
That tablet, it says "Melon".
Registration will be closing soon.
MELON
It's proof that he was just here.
So does this mean Melon
is going to be part of a turf war?
He's the boss of Shishi-Gumi after all.
Right. We should be able
to catch Melon here.
[rats stammer]
- Hey! Degoshi!
- [Bean] Do we get to know the plan?
[announcer] Registration closing.
[drumroll]
Wait. I'll compete.
[scoffs]
And you're aware of the rules?
Oh, uh... Probably.
Who the heck is this wolf?
Well, all right. Put your name down.
Wait. He's not planning to enter
the turf war alone, is he?
Gah! Stop, Degoshi!
[Legoshi] Oh...
My name...
This is bad.
I'm on the run.
If I give them my real name, uh...
Hmm. Still, I don't want
to hide behind a fake name.
I want to confront Melon fair and square.
Mmm.
Huh?
This marker's all dried up.
This one, too.
Come on.
[host 1] I can't remember the last time
we had someone new enter.
[host 2] Yeah, you're right.
[host 1] "Le-go-shi."
Well, it's legible, so you're good.
[Melon] Looks like it was
written by a simpleton.
- [Legoshi] Melon.
- Tsk.
I hope you're proud of yourself.
You really ruined my birthday.
[Legoshi] The Shishi-Gumi.
They're not here.
He's alone?
I have to admit, you've got
quite a few surprises up your sleeve.
What would a little wolf like you
do with the Black Market?
Nothing.
I just needed to find out where you were.
Well, you found me, so I think
that deserves a turf war cookie.
Oh. You want to put on a show, is that it?
If it means I can take you down,
any place will do.
[Melon] Fine by me.
What are we waiting for?
You just want to cut to the chase?
[both growl]
[host 1] Stop! Stop! Stop!
Save all this growling
for the day of the event.
Gentlemen, it's time for the quiz.
[Legoshi] Huh?
[clattering]
Hey, what-- What the heck is this?
[host 2] The Beast Society
basic knowledge quiz.
[host 1] Ferocity isn't
the only trait you need.
You want to control the Black Market,
then you better have the smarts.
[groans] You're kidding me, right?
[host 2] No way.
You might be from Shishi-Gumi,
but this is your first time.
[Melon] Seriously? Come on.
That's right.
He registered himself for the turf war.
Huh. Yeah.
Can't help but wonder
what this wolf intends to do
if he gets his hands on the Market.
The rules are simple.
Just answer the questions.
If Legoshi wins, we let him in.
If he loses, see that pointy thing?
Well, you get the picture.
- Why is it only over me?
- [Melon scoffs]
[host 2] The Shishi-Gumi has already
earned trust and demonstrated results.
Legoshi, would you like
to withdraw your application?
You go right ahead.
I can win. I'm sure.
All right, let's begin.
[dramatic sting]
What is standard fare for a bird taxi?
[ding]
- [Legoshi] Uh...
- 520 yen for passengers under three kilos.
720 if you're over that weight.
LEGOSHI - MELON
- [dinging]
- [host 2] Correct.
[dramatic sting]
What does the Turtle Public Decency
Clothing Ordinance allow?
[ding]
Full nudity is allowed as long as
there's something around their neck.
- [dinging]
- [Legoshi grumbles]
Now, tell us what emotions
are being expressed
by each of these tails.
- [ding]
- From the top.
I'm feeling very confident.
My stomach hurts.
Cleaning is going great.
I missed the season finale.
- [dinging]
- All correct!
- All right!
- [host 2] And that's four points.
Hey, this guy's a canine, you know.
It's pretty obvious that tail language
isn't a fair question for him.
Uh, you're right.
Maybe that was a little unfair.
Fine. Only one point will be awarded.
[groans] Are you kidding me?
Isn't that the wolf
the police are looking for?
Oh, that one?
[host 1] This next round of questions
will be more difficult.
[dramatic sting]
What is the best time of day
for the highest probability
of pleasant communication
between herbivores and carnivores?
- [dings]
- Really?
8:00 a.m. to 10:00 a.m.
Um, mornings are, uh...
Hey, Legoshi. Pop quiz.
Who do you think I was just
talking with in the halls?
Huh? Ah, morning scent test.
[sniffing]
I smell a male goat.
They often hang out with herbivores
in the morning, right?
It's considered polite manners
for us carnivores.
Animals that soak up the morning sun get
a nice serotonin boost to start their day.
Morning sunlight
puts everyone in a good mood.
[host 1] Hmm. Yeah, that's close enough.
- Correct!
- [dinging]
On to the next question!
[dramatic sting]
Feline pupils become larger
when in a dark place and what other time?
Buzz in now!
[dings]
[Legoshi] It's not when they
eat something delicious.
- [chuckles]
- Wait, wait, Bill.
Virgins have no right
to eat three rice balls.
That's one of my favorite. Kelp onigiri.
[grunting, swallows]
[laughs] Oh, yeah!
When they're playing
with people they care about.
- [host 1] Correct.
- [dinging]
[crowd exclaiming]
Ah! Getting the answers right is fun.
Calm down. It's just a quiz.
I didn't mean to rub it in.
I just like having the chance to learn
about everything around me.
- Even about you, Melon.
- [rope creaking]
- [snaps]
- Huh? [exclaims]
[host 1] And he's safe. [giggles]
Looks like the rope
was wearing a little thin.
[gasping] Melon?
Thank you.
Seriously? You're such a softie. [grunts]
[Legoshi] Whoa!
That's enough, isn't it?
Can we cut the crap and let the guy
join our precious turf war already?
[host 1] Very well.
Legoshi, you mark my words.
Your last gasp will be
in a pool of despair of my making.
Meat Appreciation Day.
I'll save you a seat.
See you there.
Listen, until this fight between us
is settled, keep your hands off Haru.
[scoffs] Sure.
Your grave will be a front row seat.
Your ghost will watch me savor every inch.
[fire crackling]
[melancholy music playing]
[Ogma] Did you hear me?
Louis?
Uh...
Yes?
I was asking you if everything
was going well with Azuki.
Uh, yeah.
Well, we're getting there.
[Ogma] I see.
Then I guess I'm relieved.
[exhales]
Is something worrying you?
One moment I feel like you and I
are on the exact same page.
And then suddenly,
I'm in a corner with you
snarling at me
like some ungrateful carnivore.
Tell me what's on your mind.
LOUIS SUPPORTS INTERSPECIES COUPLES
[Ogma] I thought you spoke to the mayor.
Until that rabid wolf
that ate your leg is apprehended,
we don't need you
drawing any unnecessary attention.
Is that so? Is that what he said?
If your relationship with that wolf
ends up getting exposed,
you'll be the one who suffers for it.
[sighs] I understand,
but there's something I'd like to ask.
So it looks like you're covering
many of the expenses
for the Zoolympics bid. Is that right?
Care to be more specific?
Well, to break it down,
three billion
for venue construction costs,
more for advertising,
and the Horns Conglomerate is offering
sponsorship funding to the tune of 80%.
All of this overseen by the mayor.
[exhales softly]
For you, numbers are
the most important thing.
Relationships for you are usually about
the profit they can generate,
and whether or not they can contribute
to the Horns Conglomerate's bottom line.
[rustling]
Just when did you get interested
in corporate accounting?
Ever since I found the secret ledger.
It turns out all this investing
has created quite the deficit.
So what is the angle you're playing here?
[Ogma] And since when
do I have to answer to you?
Since right now?
Am I the heir or not?
On paper, you are.
[Louis stammers, sighs]
I certainly don't remember raising a dog.
I suggest you stop sniffing around.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sighs]
[cell phone buzzing]
Huh?
KOPI LUWAK RESEARCH CENTER
[bats screech]
[cheeping]
ABNORMAL REACTIONS IN MIXED BEASTS
[Deshico]
Let's see if my hypothesis is correct.
Carnivore blood.
[bats screeching]
Herbivore blood.
[chuckles]
Why, thank you.
[hissing]
[cheeping]
The heightened senses of a hybrid
are indeed quite impressive,
but they also hold a weakness.
- [rustling]
- Huh?
[muffled grunting]
[bats screeching]
- [wind whooshing]
- [rustling]
DRAMA CLUB
[both exclaim]
[bats screeching]
[muffled grunting echoes]
[muffled grunting]
[exhales]
- [wind whooshing]
- [rustling]
[shatters]
Deshico, hey!
Come on! Wake up!
[vomits]
[coughing]
[sighs] You're alive.
[Louis] What do you remember?
[Deshico] It was Melon.
It had to have been him.
[inhales]
[sneezes]
[sighs]
Because I figured out the weakness
that hybrids have. [sniffles]
A hybrid weakness?
Yeah.
Look here.
When one mixes the blood of both
a carnivore and an herbivore,
followed by heating it,
the reaction produces a gas.
Mixed breeds seem to enter
a state of intoxication
due to a presently unknown
substance in that gas.
[exclaims] That's perfect!
If we could use this on Melon,
it'd give us the edge
we need to catch him.
Excellent work.
I can't thank you enough.
- I'll leave you to it.
- If only it were that simple.
Huh?
[Deshico] When carnivore and herbivore
blood samples are mixed together,
coagulation initiates immediately.
At that point, a gas is made,
merely for an instant.
We don't have enough
to incapacitate a beast of his size.
Hold on.
I could have sworn those research notes--
That was because a massive
amount of blood was spilled.
[sighs] So then it's...
- useless?
- Hold on a second.
Here.
HEMATOPOIETIC CELLS' EFFECTS ON BLOOD
[Louis] Hmm? What am I looking at here?
There seems to be a substance
that prevents coagulation
of interspecies blood.
If we had this,
even a small amount of blood
could produce the results
we're looking for.
That's promising.
So then, how do we get a hold
of this anticoagulant?
Well, that's up to you, I believe.
HORNS RESEARCH
[gasps] Wait. That's our institute.
That's right.
Okay, I'm on it.
Thank you again.
Wait. Hang on.
- Here.
- Keep it till you dry off.
- [door opens]
- [chuckles]
Ah! So young.
[Fudge] Well, this is just terrible.
[Kai] I guess
we'll cut back on palm trees.
We just don't have the time
to do everything.
Help me understand.
Why was all of this left
outside the storeroom?
'Cause the paint wasn't dry yet.
The weather forecast said storm.
It's easy to blame us
when you weren't there.
And it's easy to use your head.
- That's real helpful.
- [Bill] Cut it out.
Everyone just get back to work.
[Els] Yeah,
we don't have time for bickering.
[Juno] It's getting really
negative in here.
How can I help lighten the mood?
Just act like a cheerful canine?
- Hey, guys, why don't we...
- [cracks]
- [Tao exclaims]
- Huh?
[Tao stammers]
- It's no use.
- Huh?
Isn't this the point
where we just give up?
Right?
[all stammer hesitantly]
[Tao] Come on.
I know we're all thinking it
It seems like we're all out of luck.
It's even supposed to rain
at the festival.
What are we doing?
[stammers hesitantly]
[all stammer hesitantly]
[Tao] Besides,
Legoshi is wanted for devouring.
I just don't know anymore.
When I think about it,
the incident with Riz and Kiby,
the way that he got hurt...
that happened because
a carnivore was with an herbivore.
No matter how you cut it,
we've just gotta face the facts.
- Tao...
- Sorry, Kiby.
Really, the words I wrote
were just for myself.
In the end, it's just wishful thinking.
Just wishful thinking?
[Pina] So what if it is?
Huh?
The dialog is, "Someday I might eat you."
Remember that?
[Juno] That's from the play.
[Kibi] That's from the script.
"I'll go away across the bridge.
If it's a place without herbivores,
then I won't be able to hurt anyone."
[stammers] "Just wait.
Please don't go.
I don't want you to leave.
You won't eat me.
So please stay here."
[Pina] "I don't want to be the bad guy."
"I know you're just frightened."
"Well, I don't want to hurt you anymore,
because you're precious."
So tell me, is this just wishful thinking?
[stammers]
[cracks]
- [Sally] It finally cracked!
- [all] Huh?
I knew I could do it if I kept trying.
Awesome!
Right.
That's it.
Let's just try, all right?
Let's keep going to the end.
[Tao stammers]
[Tao] Okay.
All right! That's that teamwork spirit.
- Yeah!
- Let's get to work.
I'm sorry, guys.
Let's get this over here.
I'D LIKE TO SEE A RESEARCHER NAMED ROSE
[Maps voice]
Turn right in 20 meters, then proceed.
[stammers, gasps]
[Louis] Oh, no.
Zoozle Maps takes me
through the Black Market.
[panting]
[gasps]
Back then, once a month,
I was allowed to see outside.
[Legoshi] Louis?
What are you doing here?
[sighs]
Louis, you can't go in there.
You need permission.
It'll be fine.
This is my home.
What did you say?
Uh, wait. What do you mean by your home?
[Louis] Exactly what I said.
This was a wet market.
I guess you could say I was raised here.
Turned out the man that purchased me
was the chairman
of the Horns Conglomerate.
[sighs]
You don't seem too surprised.
Well, I was just trying
to match your energy.
I felt like I should just
keep my snout shut and listen.
[gentle music playing]
[door creaking]
[Ogma] You, Louis,
you'll be able to change this world.
[Louis] I've made up my mind.
I'm done playing the dutiful son.
I'm ready to do whatever I have to.
Louis,
two days from now,
I'm going to settle things with Melon.
- So you did find Melon?
- Mmm.
He's entering the turf war
as the boss of the Shishi-Gumi.
So I signed up to fight him.
Legoshi, do you know how dangerous it is?
It's a real fight, you know.
Ah. Well, that... I wanted to ask you...
if anything happens to me, would you, uh...
would you mind taking care of Haru?
I know you fought Riz,
but this is very different.
You can't do this alone.
[sighs] I want to face him
one-on-one, fair and square.
You want some help?
Huh?
An herbivore with one leg
and the carnivore who devoured it.
It seems like we'd make quite the pair.
Uh, yeah.
Right.
That's exactly what this is.
And you and me,
we've got this.
[closing theme song playing]